Contact

149 Bayview Terrace Akron, OH 44319 3306711076 (Home) rdevans87@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/ ryanevanscreative (LinkedIn) github.com/rdevans87 (Portfolio) www.ryanevanscreative.com (Personal)

Top Skills

Customer Service

Sales

Leadership

Languages

English

Certifications

Software Testing Bootcamp

Project Management Professional (PMP)

Publications

Better Call 'Breaking Bad' Actor Aaron Paul

What Does 'Hardcore Henry' Mean for Moviegoers

The Discovery of Director Ryan Coogler

Rap Artist Kid Cudi Crosses Over Terrence Malick's Creative Magic

Ryan Evans

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp at The Ohio State University
Akron

Summary

Multifaceted customer service specialist with a proficient understanding of technical troubleshooting and valuable experience supporting a variety of software products and services on the web. Self-motivated team player with a strong work ethic and desire to learn new skills in web development.

Experience

IMDb.com
Customer Service Specialist
July 2019 - Present (1 year 9 months)

Santa Monica, California

Acted quickly to diagnose and troubleshoot technical issues for IMDb's website and mobile apps under tight deadlines to meet 24-hour SLA.

- Collaborated with development team to file bug reports, track unresolved tickets, and manage customer relationships.
- Built fast and effective working relationships with team members of varying seniority, backgrounds and experience.
- Demonstrated ability to solve challenging technical issues and make datadriven decisions to improve customer satisfaction.
- Contributed to self-help knowledge base and implemented new support procedures that reduced incoming contacts and ticket resolution times.

Cast & Crew

3 years 4 months

Sr. Product Technical Support Analyst April 2018 - July 2019 (1 year 4 months)

Burbank, California

Assisted with product implementation, software QA testing, and technical support for digital payroll products and services: Studio+, Start+ (SAAS)

• Provided on-site/remote product demonstrations and training sessions to end-users.

- Collaborated with product manager and engineering team on development of implementation and end-user training.
- Tracked bug reports, enhancement requests, and software updates using Agile project management Scrum in Jira.
- Acted as liaison between senior leadership to communicate software updates and releases to customer support team.

Sales Associate, Final Draft Inc. April 2016 - April 2018 (2 years 1 month)

Burbank, California, United States

Responded to a high volume of incoming customer inquiries via phone, email, and live chat to drive sales and provide an excellent customer experience.

- Used Salesforce (CRM) to manage interactions with existing customers and identify new opportunities to increase sales.
- Assisted with QA testing and software launch of two product releases: Final Draft 10 (2016) & Final Draft 11 (2018).
- Performed in depth product demonstrations and sales presentations for industry professionals at screenwriting conferences and promotional events.
- Position required a strong attention to detail, exceptional service skills, and the ability to communicate effectively.

Unified Pictures
Production Executive
March 2015 - April 2016 (1 year 2 months)
Greater Los Angeles Area

Facilitated the relationship between financiers and executive producers on upcoming film projects.

- Communicated effectively under pressure during long periods of high call volumes to provide concise and accurate information to accredited investors.
- Gained valuable understanding of production workflow, budget costs, and private placement memorandums.
- Demonstrated flexibility and persistence to create consistent pipeline of accredited leads for finance department.

Macy's
3 years 3 months
Sales Supervisor
March 2013 - March 2015 (2 years 1 month)
Columbus, Ohio

Managed associates to provide the highest level of customer service through monitoring selling behaviors; taught detailed product knowledge, communicated policies and procedures.

- Demonstrated ability to lead a team to achieve daily sales goals and drive customer engagement with MAGIC selling best practices.
- Ability to analyze daily reports and identify opportunities to increase retail sales within assigned departments.
- Collaborated with merchandising team on upcoming promotional events and changes to department floor plans.
- Coached sales associates to connect with customers in order to build quick rapport and provide an outstanding shopping experience.

Sales Associate

January 2012 - March 2013 (1 year 3 months)

Columbus, Ohio

Duties included connecting with customers and assisting with their needs. Position required strong interpersonal skills, product knowledge, and the ability to multi-task. Demonstrated a proven track record of of exceeding daily sales goal and improving customer engagement.

University of Central Florida Production Assistant June 2009 - June 2011 (2 years 1 month)

Acted as Liaison for student affairs, responsible for maintaining a professional relationship between students and faculty at UCFtv. Duties included Floor Directing, Technical Directing, Running Teleprompter, Camera Operation, and Editing. Learned how to work effectively in a production team under tight shooting deadlines and television broadcast schedules.

Education

The Ohio State University

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp, Web Development · (2021 - 2021)

University of Central Florida

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Communication and Media Studies · (2007 - 2011)